Niva Bhupa Restore Plan vs
hdfcergo.com I will do a
full comparison of all three plans
and in the end I will tell you which company's
product is the most powerful. Do not skip the video otherwise
you might miss some important part for which
you are watching this video. So stay tuned till the end of
the video. So let's start
friends, without taking much of your time,
before that friends, if you are new
to my channel then please
subscribe to the channel. You will
get all the videos related to this here with full information.
If you feel that this video of mine has
helped you even a little, then please do like it.
Your one like will give me a
lot of support. Friends,
for example, I have taken two adults and one child. If I
talk about the elder member, then the age
criteria is 43 years and the age of the child will be
17 years. If I
talk about the sum insured, then the sum insured will be Rs. 10 lakhs.
We will understand the video completely with this example. Friends, at the
end of the video I will tell you what
How much premium will be charged for the plan? If you purchase any of these
plans, then first
see the basic details of the company and how is its entire
process. First of all, if we
talk about the hospital network, then Niva Bappa has
8600 plus network hospitals, whereas
ADFC has 10000 plus network hospitals
and if we talk about Star Health, then there are 1135
network hospitals. If we talk about claim ratio, then the
claim ratio of Niva P is
96, that of ADFC is 97, that
of Star Health is 90. Talking about claim approval time,
Niva P has also mentioned this thing on its brochure. They
guarantee 30 minutes claim approval every day. If
we talk about ADFC, then the claim approval is of two
hours, that too in 90 cases, the approval is of two hours. It is also
possible that you will get
approval before that also, but this two
hour is their maximum date. And if we talk about Star Health, then the
claim approval time in Star Health
In this also, your time is of 2 hours.
In case of 90, you get approval within two hours.
Talking about claim settlement, there is in-house claim settlement in Max B, it is
also in-house in ADAC and there is also in-house in
Star Health. Talking about the basic features of the plan, the coverage type in NB is individual and family floater. Your SEM is the same in ADAC as well. Your SEM is the same in Star Health as well.
Talking about renewability,
yours is life long in all three. Once
you enroll in the policy,
you can continue the policy for life long.
Talking about life health and benefits, there is
up to 30 in Niva P,
yours is 8 in ADFC and
yours is not available in Star Health.
Life health means that today,
Maximum Health Insurance Company has
launched an app to keep its customers fit, in
which your step count will be there and
on behavior of that step count, you will
get some points. Premium at the time of your renewal.
You will get discount in this.
Talking about the policy term,
you can take a policy for one year, two years and three years at a time in Niva B. If we
talk about HDFC,
you can take it for one year or two years.
In Star Health, you
can take a policy for only one year at a time.
Talking about long term discount, if
you take a policy together for 2 years in Niva B, then
you will get a discount of 7.5% on your second year premium.
Similarly, if you take a policy for 3 years, then
you will get a discount of 15% in the third year.
hdfc.com has a code of ₹5000000.
Up to the same code in Niva B, you
also have it in ADAC. Talking about Star Health,
it will cover your maximum single AC private
room. Talking about inpatient treatment,
you will be covered in all three.
Talking about pre-hospitalization, your cover is 90
days. Your cover is 60 days in Niva BPA. Your cover is 60 days
in HDFC. The same in Star.
Talking about post-hospitalization,
Your cover is 180 days in Niva Bupa Your cover is 180 days
in HDFC Your cover is 90 days
in Star Health Here your cover
is a little lower in Star Health as compared to these two If you
talk about day care treatment then all day
care treatments will be covered in Niva B
Same is in ADAC and same is
in Star Health If you talk about road ambulance then
you will
get ₹2000000 in Niva B If you talk about air ambulance
then you will get ₹25 lakh in Niva B Same is your
hdfcfund.com
In Star Health your limit
is set ₹1500000
cover If you talk about emergency hospitalization then
you will be covered in all three plans If you
talk about second medical opinion
then you are covered in all three If you talk about shared room
amendment then
your cover is fixed in all three If you
remain admitted for more than 24 hours and you want a
room below the one offered to you by the company
If you share the room with someone,
in that condition  If you are making a profit for the company, then the
company will transfer a benefit of ₹ per day
to your account.
Talking about Covid-19,
you will be covered under all three plans. Almost all the companies are
covering you. Talking about maternal benefit,
you are
not covered in any of the three plans. No claim bonus
in nb is at 50% up to 10 semesters.
If you do not take it for any year, then
in that condition your policy will be increased to 50%.
If you do not take it for 2 years, then
your policy will just double from 10 lakhs to
20 lakhs. Same condition applies in HDFC as
well. Talking about Star Health,
your first year will be at 25%,
after that your policy will be increased by 10% every year.
If you do not take a claim, then
talking about restore benefit, you will get
unlimited time restore benefit in niva b
and the best thing is that here this is applicable
for the same person and same amount as well.
Your benefit will be applicable. Suppose
you have a policy of 10 lakhs, if that 10 lakhs gets
fully adjusted, if you have to get admitted again in the same year
and
your basic sum in your policy has been exhausted, then
in that condition the company will
restore ₹ lakhs again and you
can get the entire treatment done up to 10 lakhs. If we
talk about Optima Restore, then
you will get the restore benefit once in it and
here also your same person will get the same benefit
applicable on the same amount. If we talk about Star
Health, then you will get it thrice in Star Health,
but the condition in Star Health is that it will
not be applicable on the same person and the same amount. If we talk about organ donor, then your
cover is up to the maximum, your cover is up to the maximum in Niva B,
your cover is up to the maximum in ADAC. If we
talk about Star Health, then the
maximum limit of ₹ 1 lakh is ₹ lakh. The
company will not pay more than 1 lakh if ​​we talk about modern treatment.
First of all, let me tell you about
modern treatment.  Like robotic surgery or
advanced surgery etc.,
all these come under modern treatment, the
maximum company has started covering
this thing, Niva B has set a limit of
1 lakh, you
can get your treatment up to 1 lakh, under ADAC
you are covered up to 10 lakh, whereas if we
talk about Star Health, then some limit
is decided here but if you
go and see on its website then you will know the limit,
different rates are fixed according to different diseases, if we
talk about co-payment then there is
no co-payment in Niva B at any
age,
if you purchase the policy at the age of 61 or above then
you will have to pay a co-payment of 20%, as many
times as your hospital bills come, there will be
your sharing of 20% in it, you will have to pay 20%, if we
talk about new born baby, then
your new born baby is not covered in ADAC
also, but you are being
covered here in Star, after
16 days the company will cover you and here the
limit  Your out of pocket insurance will be Rs 10 per month
or maximum Rs 50,000. If we talk about OPD expenses, then
you are
not covered in any of the three. Let's talk about
optional on coverage. Apart from this, you
want to add some optional items in your policy.
First of all, non-payable item which we
call consumer benefit,
is optional for you in your Niva Bappa. You can add it, it will be in the
name of safeguard.
If you add it, then a
little extra premium will be charged and
all your non-payable items will be covered. There is
no option in ADAC nor is there an
option in your star. Talking about hospital,
here also you have an option in Niva Bappa.
For this also,
you can add on hospital cash by paying a little more premium. The
benefit that you will get under this is that if you are admitted for more than 24 hours, then
in that condition the
company will pay you some cash per day, it will
depend on your basic cess. If we
talk about hdfcfund.com, then your nv is covered.  It is
not available in your ADAC,
you can get it added on by paying a little extra premium
and this is also not available in Star Health. Let
us talk about exclusions,
first of all the initial waiting
period, like all the companies have
kept an initial waiting period of 30 days, but
in that 30 days, if there is any accident injury, then
you can get your treatment related to it,
otherwise if you have to get any treatment related to it, then
you will have to wait for 30 days. If
we talk about specific diseases, then all the
three companies have
kept a waiting period of 24 months, for
diseases which take time to develop,
you can get your treatment done after 24 months. For
pre-existing diseases, if you have
already disclosed any disease to the
company, then for that you will have to
wait for 36 months in Niva B, that is,
you will have to wait for 3 years in HDFC,
in Star Health you will have to wait for full 4
years, so friends, as
I told you  I told you that in the end of the video
I will tell you which product
is the most powerful and
how much premium you will have to pay to take which plan, so first of all
let's talk about premium, if you purchase
n b's resource plan then
its premium will be
₹2500000, friends, if I talk about
which plan has the most
benefits, if
you are looking according to your budget and if you are searching for a good plan, then
I think n b
re is the best plan and friends I would
like to tell you one more thing, which
I have recently researched, the
product which is selling the most in the market right now is n
b resource plan,
friends if you look at it according to premium then
your Star Health is the cheapest plan,
after that n b rester plan is something like
₹2000000, whereas
if we talk about ADAC then it is a much more
expensive plan, if you can afford then
you can take that plan, but
if I tell you more features than that, which right now  Till now
I have done the comparison and as far as
I have analyzed which company's
product is the most powerful, I
think that according to the budget, nma Bupa
Resource Plan will be the best and effective, the
reason for this is that in this plan, the
benefit of unlimited time retirement is available for the same person, same amount and the
premium is also quite affordable for you.
Friends, here is the comparison video of all the three plans till now, in which
I have compared you with full details. If
you think
which of the three plans, nb ADAC and Star Health, is the best suitable for you
or which plan do you have,
you can tell me by commenting below
or if you have any
query related to this plan, then you can also ask me
directly, you can either email me
or
you can ask me by commenting below, so thank you so much
friends, stay tuned.
In the next video, we will review some other plan
or
compare some other plan. If you liked this video
Really, if this is an information video for you, then
please do like the video and
share it with as many people as possible. See you very soon in the next video, we will
review some other plan
or compare some other plan. Till then, thank you.
Thank you so much. Jai
Hind.